A Guide to the Warren Weaver papers FA419
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1912-1978; 1; 5.5 Cubic Feet
  The strength of the papers is a rich set of correspondence, primarily contained in Series 1, which are arranged as received by RAC in four subseries: 1. General Correspondence, 1925-1977; 2. General Correspondence, 1912-1978; 3. Probability; 4. World Wars.
  The General Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by personal or institutional name, and further presented loosely in reverse chronological order within each folder.
  - General Correspondence, 1925-1977; 1
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science (A.A.A.S.), 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Academy of Religion and Mental Health, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Academy of Religion and Mental Health, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Academy of Religion and Mental Health, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Alice TV Show (WNET-TV Channel 13), 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5.1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Author's Guild, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Ayer, N.W., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Ba-Bl, 1954-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bo-Bu, 1959-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Beadle, George, 1961-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Binet, Francis E., 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bowers, John Z., 1961-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Brant, Selwyn A., 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Broughton, Philip S., 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Brown, C. Victor, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Burhoe, Ralph W., 1967-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bush, Vannevar, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - C, 1963-1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cheese, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Clark, Richard, 1962-1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Compton, Randolph, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Conant, J.B., 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Cooper, James Gregory, 1963-1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Corner, George, 1963-1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Cost of Living (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Courant, Richard, 1965-1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences (NYU): Correspondence, 1963-1973 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences (NYU): Publications, 1953-1969 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1958-1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - D, 1959-1973 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Davis, Harold L: Scientific Research, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Dubridge, Lee A., 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - E, 1956-1972 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Reports from Ellen, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - F, 1942-1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Fisher Radio, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Fosdick, Raymond, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Foundation Library Center, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - G, 1937-1973 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Geiger, Jack, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Gould, Lawrence, 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - H, 1954-1978 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Harrar, George, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Harrod, Sir Roy, 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Hayek, F.A.V., 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Hazeltine, Allen, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Heffner, Richard, 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Holter, Heinz, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Horton, Philip, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Hunt, R.N., 1959-1972 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - I, 1937-1952 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Ingraham, Mark, 1961-1972 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - J, 1961-1972 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Jellinek, Roger, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Jones, Donald, 1963-1973 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - K, 1960-1974 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - L, 1951-1973 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Lenard, Alexander, 1961-1967 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Luria, Zella (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - M, 1953-1973 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Mahoney, Margaret, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Mason, Max, 1925-1960 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Miller, H.M., Jr., 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1929-1977 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Monod, Jacques, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Morison, Robert S., 1959-1973 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - N, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1958-1973 (Box 6, Folder 69)
    - National Academy of Sciences: Math Awards Committee, 1968-1974 (Box 6, Folder 70)
    - National Cash Register, 1942-1967 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Neubert, A.K., 1966-1973 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - Neyman, Jerzy, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Nobel Prize, 1951-1962 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Nourse, Edwin G., 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - O, 1946-1972 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - P, 1960-1971 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Piel, Gerard, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Poitras, Edward, 1960-1971 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Polanyi, Michael, 1958-1968 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Pomerat, G.R., 1967-1971 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Q, 1955-1967 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - R, 1959-1978 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Randall, H.T., 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Redbook (Robert Lewis), 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Reedsburg Hardware Company, 1957-1973 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Rhind, Flora, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Rhoads, C.P., 1959 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Roberts, Walter Orr, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Robinson, Edward, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Rockefeller Foundation: Villa Serbelloni, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Rossoni, Dina, 1967-1969 (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - Roston, Leo, 1966-1973 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1959-1972 (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - S, 1959-1973 (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Saturday Review, 1968-1972 (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Savage, Jimmie, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Save the Children Federation, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Save the Children Federation (Box 8, Folder 98.1)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Permanently Restricted - Confidential Material - Personnel
    - Scientists' Institute for Public Information, 1966-1972 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Skipper, Howard: Southern Research Institute, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Slichter, Louis, 1966-1973 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Stanford Meeting, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Stevens, David, 1967-1972 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Stibitz, George R., 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Stolper, Wolf, 1966-1968 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - T, 1958-1973 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Taylor, Barney, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 107)
    - U, 1959-1971 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - V, 1966-1974 (Box 8, Folder 109)
    - W, 1952-1973 (Box 8, Folder 110)
    - W, 1958-1973 (Box 8, Folder 111)
    - Wald, George, 1959-1969 (Box 8, Folder 112)
    - Wallis, W. Allen, 1961-1973 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Watson, James, 1966-1973 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Webster (Dictionary), 1952-1966 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    - Wernimont, Ken, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - Whiteside, Derek, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 117)
    - Wilks, S.S., 1950-1959 (Box 9, Folder 118)
    - Williams, John, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 119)
    - Williams, Roger J., 1959-1968 (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - Wisconsin, University of, 1965-1973 (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - Wolfle, D., 1963-1970 (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Woodford, Peter, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 123)
    - XYZ, 1964-1970 (Box 9, Folder 124)
  - General Correspondence, 1912-1978; 2
    - General (Box 9, Folder 125)
    - A-B (Box 9, Folder 126)
    - C (Box 9, Folder 127)
    - D (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - E-F (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - G (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - H-J (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - K-L (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - M (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - N-O (Box 10, Folder 134)
    - P-Q (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - R (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - S (Box 10, Folder 137)
    - T-U-V (Box 10, Folder 138)
    - W (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Probability, 3
    - Correspondence, 1949-1966 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    - Articles (by Others), 1955-1968 (Box 10, Folder 141)
  - World Wars, 4
    - Correspondence, 1941-1948 (Box 10, Folder 142)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1948 (Box 10, Folder 142A)
      Restricted from access.
    - Bowman Committee-Bush Report, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 143)
    - Air Raid Warden (Box 10, Folder 144)
    - English Trip, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 145)
    - General, 1943-1955 (Box 10, Folder 146)
    - Congratulations, Honors, 1942-1948 (Box 10, Folder 147)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes citations for the King?s Medal and the National Medal of Merit
    - Congratulations, Honors, 1942-1948 (Box 10, Folder 147A)
    - The New Yorker, 1944-1946 (Box 11, Folder 148)
      Including Hiroshima article.
    - Posters (Box 11, Folder 149)
    - Naval Research Advisory Committee, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - Passes and Identification Cards (Box 11, Folder 151)
    - Newspaper Clippings: Critical Events, 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 152)
    - U.S. Naval Decorations and Code Lists (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - World War I Service: Private and Second Lieutenant, Air Service, 1918-1919 (Box 11, Folder 154)
- Biographical, 1932-1978; 2; 0.5 Cubic Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The biographical material, Series 2, is quite limited. Various folders or items within the collection may contain informational notes handwritten by Weaver's daughter Helen while she was reviewing the records and preparing them for shipment to RAC.
  - Biographical: General, 1932-1978 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Autobiographical, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Biographical Data (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Reviews of Works by Warren Weaver (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Occasions Attended, 1938-1957 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Occasions Attended, 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Obituaries and Condolence Letters, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 161)
    Passing of Warren Weaver.
  - Doodles (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Doodle Collection (Box 12, Folder 163)
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1933-1961; 3; 2.5 Cubic Feet
  The Rockefeller Foundation files (Series 3) include a variety of programs essays and reports as well as a limited selection of advisory committee reports. The strength of this series lies with the files documenting the interviews of Warren Weaver conducted by Barbara Rand of the Columbia University Oral History Research Office in 1961. The transcripts available in Series 3 include Weaver's written edits and comments. The final published version of the 1961 oral history is available at Columbia University and in Record Group 13 of the Rockefeller Foundation records at RAC.
  Biographical / Historical
  Weaver began his career at the Rockefeller Foundation as Director of the Division of Natural Sciences, 1932-55. He was seconded from the Foundation for a series of civilian service appointments during World War II beginning in 1941. Weaver contracted Meniere's Disease (ear infection) after the war, and was unable to resume his duties with the RF until 1946. He was appointed Director of the Division of Science and Agriculture, 1951-1955, and named Vice President for Natural and Medical Sciences, 1955-59. He retired from the Rockefeller Foundation in 1959.
  - Program Essays (WW) (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Notes for Officers, 1939-1951 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - Notes on Officers? Techniques (Natural Sciences) (Box 13, Folder 166)
  - Memos by Dean Rusk (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Memos by Others (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Natural Sciences Program Statements and Reports, 1933-1936 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Natural Sciences Program Statements and Reports, 1937-1951 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Other Program Reports (Including Agriculture), 1951-1955 (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - Appraisal Committee Reports, 1934-1939 (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Appraisal Committee Reports, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Charts used by Warren Weaver, 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 174)
  - Retirement Speeches, 1949-1953 (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - Humorous memos, poems, articles and writings (Box 14, Folder 176)
  - Oral History Transcripts of Interviews by Barbara Rand, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, 1961
  - Oral History: Interview 1, 1961 March 15 (Box 14, Folder 177)
  - Oral History: Interview 2, 1961 March 20 (Box 14, Folder 178)
  - Oral History: Interview 3, 1961 March 22 (Box 14, Folder 179)
  - Oral History: Interview 4, 1961 March 30 (Box 14, Folder 180)
  - Oral History: Interview 5, 1961 April 6 (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - Oral History: Interview 6, 1961 April 12 (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - Oral History: Interview 7, 1961 April 27 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - Oral History: Interview 8, 1961 May 5 (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Oral History: Interview 9, 1961 May 10 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Oral History: Interview 10, 1961 May 17 (Box 14, Folder 186)
  - Oral History, Interview 11, 1961 June 1 (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - Oral History, Interview 12, 1961 June 6 (Box 15, Folder 188)
  - Oral History, Interview 14, 1961 June 16 (Box 15, Folder 189)
  - Oral History, Interview 15, 1961 June 28 (Box 15, Folder 190)
  - J. George Harrar. Strategy Toward the Conquest of Hunger. New York: Rockefeller Foundation, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 191)
    Rockefeller Foundation, 1967 (w/personal inscription from JGH to WW)
  - Mexico Trip, 1946 September-October (Box 15, Folder 523)
    photograph album
  - Mexican Agricultural Program Reports [Spanish], 1947-1949 (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - Mexican Agricultural Program, photograph album (Box 16, Folder 193)
  - Mexican Agricultural Program, photograph album (Box 16, Folder 194)
  - Mexican Agricultural Program, 1956; photograph album (Box 16, Folder 195)
- Travel, 1932-1961; 4; 1.5 Cubic Feet
  Series 4 documents Weaver's travels from 1932-1961 including a chronological record of his travel for the period 1932-1938 and travel diaries for trips to Poland (1958) and England (1961).
  The series also contains a variety of travel ephemera and memorabilia including maps, guidebooks, and souvenirs primarily from Weaver's world tour in 1961.
  - Chronological Record of Travel, 1932-1938 (Box 17, Folder 196)
  - Travel Diaries and Letters, 1941-1957 (Box 17, Folder 197)
  - Travel Diary: England, 1961 March 3-April 28 (Box 17, Folder 198)
    As member of official scientific mission appointed by President Roosevelt from the membership of the National Defense Research Committee.
  - Travel Diary: England (copy), 1961 March 3-April 28 (Box 17, Folder 199)
  - Travel Diary: Poland, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 200)
  - Travel Ephemera and Memorabilia
  - Europe, 1938 (Box 17, Folder 201)
  - Europe, Spring 1948 (Box 17, Folder 202)
  - Mexico and South America, 1946-1947 (Box 18, Folder 203)
  - South America, 1949 September-October (Box 18, Folder 204)
  - Miscellaneous Travel: India, Israel, Kenya, 1954; 1959 (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - Israel: Guidebooks, Maps, Souvenirs, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Europe, Poland: News Clippings and Photographs, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 207)
  - Burma, undated (Box 18, Folder 208)
  - Japan, undated (Box 18, Folder 209)
  - World Tour 1961: Japan (Box 18, Folder 210)
  - World Tour 1961: Tokyo News Conference (Box 18, Folder 211)
  - World Tour 1961: Souvenirs (Box 18, Folder 212)
  - World Tour 1961: Tokyo (Box 18, Folder 213)
  - World Tour 1961: Kyoto (Box 18, Folder 214)
  - World Tour 1961: Nikko (Box 18, Folder 215)
  - World Tour 1961: Guidebooks, Maps, Souvenirs (Box 19, Folder 216)
  - World Tour 1961: Guidebooks, Maps, Souvenirs (Box 19, Folder 217)
  - World Tour 1961: Guidebooks, Maps, Souvenirs (Box 19, Folder 218)
  - Passports (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - Passport Applications and Documentation, 1932-1959 (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - Passports, Immunization Records (Box 19, Folder 221)
- The Salk Institute for Biological Studies, 1961-1973; 5; 4 Cubic Feet
  Series 5 contains meeting records, correspondence, reports and publicity and fundraising files documenting Weaver's activities at the Salk Institute of Biological Studies where he served as a Trustee, Chairman of the Board, and as a non-resident fellow.
  - Board of Trustees: By-Laws, 1961-1967 (Box 20, Folder 222)
  - Board of Trustees: Budgets and Costs, 1950-1954 (Box 20, Folder 223)
  - Board of Trustees: Membership, 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 224)
  - Board of Trustees: Minutes, 1963-1964 (Box 20, Folder 225)
  - Board of Trustees: Minutes, 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 226)
  - Board of Trustees: Minutes and Agendas, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 227)
  - Board of Trustees: Minutes, 1968-1971 (Box 21, Folder 228)
  - Trustees: Phone and Addresses of Staff (Box 21, Folder 229)
  - Fellows: Director's Report to Fellows, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 230)
  - Fellows: Conference Committee (Box 21, Folder 231)
  - Fellows: Meetings, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 232)
  - Fellows: Meetings, 1965-1967 (Box 22, Folder 233)
  - Fellows: Meetings, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 234)
  - Fellows: Meetings, 1964-1973 (Box 22, Folder 235)
  - Fellows: New Fellows, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 236)
  - General Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 23, Folder 237)
  - Biology and Humanities, 1969 (Box 23, Folder 238)
  - Council for Biology in Human Affairs, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 239)
  - Council for Biology in Human Affairs: Papers, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 240)
  - Neuroscience, 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 241)
  - Bronowski, Bruno, 1961-1973 (Box 23, Folder 242)
  - Cancer Research (Box 23, Folder 243)
  - Cohn, Mel, 1967-1970 (Box 23, Folder 244)
  - Conn, George, 1964-1968 (Box 24, Folder 245)
  - Crichton, Michael, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 246)
  - Fletcher, F.T., 1965-1969 (Box 24, Folder 247)
  - Glazier, Bill, 1962-1964 (Box 24, Folder 248)
  - Glazier, Bill, 1965-1973 (Box 24, Folder 249)
  - Guillemin, Roger, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 250)
  - de Hoffman, Frederic, 1971-1973 (Box 24, Folder 251)
  - Kinzel, Gus, 1964-1972 (Box 24, Folder 252)
  - Mang, Robert A., 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 253)
  - O?Connor, Basil, 1962-1971 (Box 24, Folder 254)
  - Piel, Gerard, 1965-1966 (Box 24, Folder 255)
  - Salk, Jonas, 1953 July 27 (Box 24, Folder 256)
  - Salk, Jonas, 1962-1971 (Box 25, Folder 257)
  - Slater, Joseph, 1968-1971 (Box 25, Folder 258)
  - Szilard, Leo, 1957; 1964-1965 (Box 25, Folder 259)
  - Weaver (Letters for) (Box 25, Folder 260)
  - Memoranda, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 261)
  - Future of Salk Institute: Report, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 262)
  - Future of Salk Institute: Working Group Report, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 263)
  - Program, Policy, Plans, Budget, 1962-1967 (Box 26, Folder 264)
  - Library, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 265)
  - Fundraising, undated (Box 26, Folder 266)
  - Fundraising: Publicity, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 267)
  - Appeals to Foundations, 1963-1969 (Box 26, Folder 268)
  - Appeals to Foundations, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 269)
  - Salk and Sloan Foundation, 1963-1964 (Box 26, Folder 270)
  - Publicity, 1963-1966 (Box 27, Folder 271)
  - Newsletters, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 272)
  - Photographs, 1963-1966 (Box 27, Folder 273)
  - Articles and Speeches: Salk and O'Connor, 1961-1965 (Box 27, Folder 274)
  - Warren Weaver Financial, 1963-1966 (Box 27, Folder 275)
  - Salk Institute Expenses, 1962-1965 (Box 27, Folder 276)
- Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, 1959-1974; 6; 3.5 Cubic Feet
  The records in Series 6 include documentation of select Board of Trustees meetings, staff meetings, and annual reports during Weaver's tenure at Sloan. This series also contains correspondence and reports, principally Weaver's correspondence with Alfred P. Sloan from 1959-1966.
  - General, 1966-1973 (Box 27, Folder 277)
  - Case, Everett, 1962-1971 (Box 27, Folder 278)
  - Program Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 28, Folder 279)
  - Donner Frederic, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 280)
  - Farinholt, L.H., 1966-1971 (Box 28, Folder 281)
  - Hermann, Robert, 1966-1970 (Box 28, Folder 282)
  - Josephs, Devereux, 1966-1967 (Box 28, Folder 283)
  - Klivington, Ken, 1969-1974 (Box 28, Folder 284)
  - Kreidler, Robert, 1966-1971 (Box 28, Folder 285)
  - Mathematics Memo (Box 28, Folder 286)
    Mathematics Memo, Evaluative comments on A.P. Sloan Foundation Grants for Mathematics.
  - Mathematics Proposal, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 287)
  - Neurosciences, 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 288)
  - New Program, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 289)
  - Procedures on Processing New Grants, 1954 (Box 29, Folder 290)
  - Wessell, Nils, 1968-1974 (Box 29, Folder 291)
  - Zurcher, Arnold, 1967-1968 (Box 29, Folder 292)
  - Special Report to Trustees: ?A Proposed Operational Concept for the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation", 1969 (Box 29, Folder 293)
  - Mathematics Program, 1966-1968 (Box 29, Folder 294)
  - Biology of Behavior, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 295)
  - Project Advice, 1966-1971 (Box 29, Folder 296)
  - Hampshire College, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 297)
  - Harvard Project: Physics, 1966-1968 (Box 30, Folder 298)
  - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1953-1955 (Box 30, Folder 299)
  - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1967 July 10-December 29 (Box 30, Folder 300)
  - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1968 January 4-June 26 (Box 30, Folder 301)
  - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1968 July 3-December 24 (Box 30, Folder 302)
  - Business Memos, 1960-1961 (Box 30, Folder 303)
  - Secretarial Services, 1966-1973 (Box 30, Folder 304)
  - Contractual Agreements, 1957-1975 (Box 31, Folder 305)
  - Disbursements: Five Year Projection: Income Authorization and Disbursement, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 306)
  - Expense Account, 1962-1968 (Box 31, Folder 307)
  - Program and Policy, 1962-1966 (Box 31, Folder 308)
  - Mr. Sloan: WW Personal, 1959-1966 (Box 31, Folder 309)
  - Memos to Mr. Sloan, 1959-1960 (Box 31, Folder 310)
  - Memos to Mr. Sloan, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 311)
  - Memos to Mr. Sloan, 1962 (Box 31, Folder 312)
  - Memos to Mr. Sloan, 1963 (Box 32, Folder 313)
  - Memos to Mr. Sloan, 1964 (Box 32, Folder 314)
  - Memos to Mr. Sloan, 1965-1966 (Box 32, Folder 315)
  - Executive and Policy Committee, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 316)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 317)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1967 April (Box 32, Folder 318)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1967 July (Box 32, Folder 319)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1967 October (Box 32, Folder 320)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1954 June 17 (Box 32, Folder 321)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1968 April (Box 32, Folder 322)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1968 July (Box 33, Folder 323)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1968 October (Box 33, Folder 324)
  - Board of Trustees Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 325)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Annual Reports, 1955-1960 (Box 33, Folder 326)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Annual Reports, 1961-1965 (Box 34, Folder 327)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Annual Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 34, Folder 328)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Annual Reports, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 329)
  - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Annual Reports, 1972-1974 (Box 35, Folder 330)
- Sloan Kettering Institute, 1959-1973; 7; 0.8 Cubic Feet
  The records in Series 7 primarily document the mid to late 1960s.
  Weaver served Sloan-Kettering Institute in a variety of administrative capacities including as a member of the Board of Scientific Consultants, 1951-1954; Trustee, 1954-1967; Chairman of the Committee on Scientific Policy, 1955-59; Executive Committee member, 1956-1967; and Vice President, 1958-1959.
  His service to Memorial Hospital and Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer included as a member of the Board, Memorial Center for Cancer and Allied Diseases, 1958-1960; Vice Chairman of the Board, Chairman of the Committee on Scientific Policy, Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center, 1960-1967; and as a member of the Executive Committee, Memorial Hospital for Cancer and Allied Diseases, 1960-1967.
  - General, 1966-1973 (Box 35, Folder 331)
  - Biomathematics, 1966-1968 (Box 35, Folder 332)
  - Committee on Scientific Policy, 1966-1968 (Box 35, Folder 333)
  - Board of Scientific Consultants, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 334)
  - Horsfall, Frank, 1959-1968 (Box 35, Folder 335)
  - Trustees, 1968-1973 (Box 35, Folder 336)
  - Minutes: Center and Hospital Executive Committees, 1966-1968 (Box 36, Folder 337)
  - Minutes: MSKCC: Board of Trustees, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 338)
  - Minutes: Memorial Hospital, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 339)